# Luis Inga Rivera

https://www.luisingarivera.website

#### **Professional Profile**

Seasoned professional in IT and computer systems with more than 15 years of experience in functional analysis and software development. I am a <u>AWS certified</u> developer with solid knowledge of programming languages such as Python, Java, JavaScript, C++, C web solutions: CSS, HTML, and passionate about Generative AI models

Creative and critical spirit, proactive, good team player, enjoys new challenges and expanding horizons.

# **Professional Experience**

## (07/2024 - Present) Full Stack Developer - Al Learning Assistant app

- Experience with chatbot and dynamic websites development.
- Experience with configuration of the chatbot, creating prompts, working with data, as well as assisting with workflows and conversational features.
- Experience monitoring and adjusting parameters to optimize a model's performance.
- Knowledge of software and analytical training.
- Proven expertise and experience in Generative AI models, architectures, algorithms, and applications.

**Technologies used:** React native (Expo), Python (Flask), MongoDB, ChatGPT API, Typescript, Node, Nginx, Supabase.

# (04/2016 - 07/2024) Front End Developer (Permanent) - Capita PLC(UK) https://www.capita.com

- Migration of Web Dynpro java application from legacy systems into SAP Fiori applications.
- Implementing new user interfaces following the SAP Fiori design guidelines and elements such as list reports, object pages, flexible-column layouts, etc.
- Definition of OData models to use it in Fiori apps using one and/or two ways binding.
- Deploying Fiori applications from SAP Web IDE or BAS into SAP Launchpad.
- Recovered German system failure impacting thousand employees after I identified it was due to misconfiguration during systems migration.
- Improved the user experience from legacy systems by identifying and fixing bugs and optimizing legacy code.

Technologies used: UI5, OData v2, CDS view, S/4HANA, Java, JSP, JQuery, Typescript, XML, CSS, HTML, Dojo, Git

## (11/2015 - 03/2016) Full Stack Developer (Contractor) - ParkwayLogic(UK)

Development of Front and Backend for a Trading System.

Technologies used: AngularJS, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL, Linux, AWS.

# 07/2015 - 09/2015 Full Stack Developer (Contractor) - Brokd(UK)

Development of dashboard pages and building an Android app.

**Technologies used:** AngularJS, JQuery, Jasmine, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Git, Java, Guice, XML, JUnit, Android Studio.

## 04/2015 - 06/2015 Front End Developer - SuperAwesome(UK) www.superawesome.tv

Development of responsive web pages for advertising companies.

Technologies used: JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, JSON, HTTP, HTML, CSS, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Git

#### 03/2014 - 01/2015 Front End Developer - Lytespark(UK)

Development of video conferencing services using <u>webRTC</u>(Real-time Communication Between Browsers)

- To develop and embed new services (chrome extension) such as screen-sharing for video conference, using Chrome API.
- Seek continuous improvement (e.g. providing new graphic functionalities) and maintain the current development.
- To support and provide video conferencing services through REST API.
- To check cross-browser compatibility (Chrome, Firefox, Opera, Safari & IE).

Technologies used: WebRTC, Real-time, Low-latency, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, JADE, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, RESTful, NodeJS, Mongodb, Git

10/2013 - 01/2014 Analyst - Alten (Spain) https://www.alten.com/

# Gas Natural Project (Electric & Gas company)

To coordinate and support functional and development teams for the implementation of the new web application.

- Coordination of different stages of the migration process through Redmine and ensuring that the requirements compliance of the new application (testing code and checking values into database through SQL queries).
- Business process re-engineering (Collecting the legacy system documents and specifications).
- Validation of technical designs and development requirements.
- Validation of requested requirements by functional teams (shared documents through SharePoint).

Technologies used: Java, ODD, Eclipse, SQL, SharePoint, Redmine, Subversion.

10/2010 - 08/2012 Analyst / Back-end Developer – Everis (Spain) https://es.nttdata.com/

## Axa Project (Insurance company – cars division)

Collection and analysis of requirements and interface designs in the development and integration environments for a new insurance policy management system.

- Analysis of the car insurance new business system to define various interface components responsible for communication management with other systems (i.e. TIREA systems)
- Analysis of processes such as validation and work flows for each component (i.e. enroll module, payment management module) to produce interface technical documentation (UML and use cases)
- Definition and development of testing software in development and integration environments

Technologies used: JavaEE, Python, ODD, Eclipse, SQL and TOAD, Jira.

## Sanitas Project (health insurance company)

Development and maintenance of J2EE applications for Sanitas contracting website.

- Maintenance of J2EE source code (MVC framework) for incident resolution and testing SQL statement performance.
- Implementation of new features and improvements (i.e. add email alerts, medical dates history)
- Deployment of improvements and new features (using WebLogic server)

Technologies used: J2EE, ODD, NetBeans, SQL and TOAD, Oracle WebLogic, ORD, JSP, VMWare, Subversion.

#### MAUI-Telefónica Project (telecommunications provider)

Functional design and validation process of the commercial and portfolio structure in Telefonica new standardized portal.

- Analysis of the commercial structure of the legacy business systems to allow integration with the new system
- Validation of clients' proposals after analysis of the legacy system.
- Production of technical documentation (UML and use cases) for developers.
- Definition of the unit, integration and system testing

Technologies used: Java, JSP, Eclipse, UML, Rational Rose, SharePoint, TortoiseSVN, Subversion.

## 10/2007 - 07/2010 Analyst/Developer - Dynasty Technology Group (Spain)

Analysis of requirements and banking software development according to the JXFS standard (Java eXtensions for Financial Services). Software development for banking devices such as pinpads, ATMs, check reader, printers, etc.

- Analysis of requirements for each device (as per manufacturer specification) and delivery date calculation
- Code implementation in Linux and Windows environments
- Software testing before delivery to the client (using JUnit)
- Technical support and solution of incidents

Technologies used: Java, C++, Eclipse, Visual Basic, UML, Rational Rose, JUnit, VMware, JNI, Subversion, Linux.

# Academic background

AWS Certified DevOps Engineer - Professional SAP Certified Development Associate - SAP Fiori Application Developer **Complutense University of Madrid** 

Madrid, Spain Master's degree in information technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

10/2008 - 09/2013

07/2020 London, UK

03/2018 London, UK

10/2004 - 09/2007